# STEPHON SMITH

Orlando, FL

Phone: (443) 610-0720 | Email: SmithWrestling89@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/stephonsmith89 | GitHub: https://www.github.com/SmithBWare89 | Portfolio:

https://smithbware89.github.io/REACT-Portfolio/

### SUMMARY

To improve business and consumer impact by implementing years of hands-on and educational experience involving full stack web development, business operations, customer service, data entry and analysis, and consistently performing under high pressure situations in front of over 700,000 viewers.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

**Languages/Frameworks:** JavaScipt ES6+, HTML, CSS, SQL, NoSQL, React, Sequelize, Vue, Node, Object Oriented Programming, Model View Controller (MVC), Express, Progressive Web Applications (PWA), REST API's

**Applications:** GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, MySQL WorkBench, GitBash, VS Code, Microsoft Office Suite, Git

**Qualities:** Team Leadership, Process Improvement, Highly Adaptable, Healthcare Knowledge & Experience, Organizational Communication, Strong Attention To Detail, Customer Service

## **PROJECTS**

## Drinkology | https://tinyurl.com/Drinkology | https://tinyurl.com/DrinkologyApp

- Summary: Full stack web application that uses the MVC pattern to create models for data to be stored using Sequelize, Handlebars template engine to construct the views, and Express to handle the API endpoints that serve data to the user on the front end.
- Role: Front End, API/Server Setup, User/Post Modeling
- Languages/Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Express, Node, MySQL, Handlebars

## Redux Refactor | https://tinyurl.com/ReduxRepo | https://tinyurl.com/ReduxECommerce

- Summary: This project is a demonstration of a MERN application. I took source code provided and converted a REST API into one that connects (M)ongo, (E)xpress, (R)eact, and (N)ode together. This is done by creating a working React server using the Apollo package as well as GraphQL to create queries that serve up data on the front end from MongoDB. The front-end work was previously created and the majority of this work was back-end development.
- Role: Refactoring REST API to MERN
- Languages/Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Apollo, MongoDB, MySQL, Node

## So-Shul-API | https://tinyurl.com/SoShulRepo | https://tinyurl.com/SoShulApp

• **Summary:** This project is intended to be a demonstration of a RESTful API using a combination of MongoDB, Express, Mongoose, and Moment. It's been expanded to

include a minimalist front end to allow for a web app representation of the data being created in our database. Further developments for this project would be to update the formatting of the project along with streamlining the API routes.

- Role: Solo project. Established the API routes and set up the front end.
- Languages/Tools: Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Bcrypt, HTML, Javascript, CSS, SQL, NoSQL, Handlebars

#### EXPERIENCE

# Referee/Floor Manager **World Wrestling Entertainment**

Oct 2019 - Sept 2021

Orlando, FL

Managing flow of matches for live events and shows consisting of ensuring talent was in the designated area, audience engagement and participation was high, and each match would run smoothly. Trained small teams averaging 10 people quarterly on basic match operations including but not limited to ring setup and breakdown processes, performance best practices, and how to utilize referees during high pressure situations.

Key Accomplishments:

- Worked on consecutive weeks of television in high pressure dynamic environments.
- Floor managed for consecutive weeks of television while also maintaining other duties.

# **Network Operations Coordinator 4** Humana

Oct 2018 – Oct 2019

Louisville, KY

Oversaw the installation, maintenance, and termination of physician and medical facility contracts for several health groups within North Carolina. This involved researching the database to analyze any current format for the physician or facility and submitting tasks for provider installation associates to complete.

# **Provider Installation Representative** Humana

Mar 2017 – Oct 2018

Louisville, KY

Oversaw the installation, maintenance, and termination of physician and medical facility contracts for several health groups within the Southern and MidWest regions. Other duties involved researching current load for physicians and facilities and monitoring the pipeline for task completion.

Key Accomplishments:

 Received STAR Award in recognition of resolving provider issues in the LA and TN markets.

## **Provider Installation Professional** Humana

Mar 2015 – Mar 2017

Louisville, KY

Performed the installation, maintenance, and termination for various Humana market physicians and facilities. Tasks included performing updates to legacy code for 150+ physicians, medical groups, and/or medical facilities to ensure files were up to date with current standards. Data analysis, time management, organization, and teamwork were essential. Key Accomplishments:

Received STAR Award in recognition of accomplishments in contract load.

**Clinical Guidance Specialist** Humana

Dec 2013 – Mar 2015

Louisville, KY

Performed the installation, maintenance, and termination for various Humana market physicians and facilities. Tasks included performing updates to legacy code for 150+ physicians, medical groups, and/or medical facilities to ensure files were up to date with current standards. Data analysis, time management, organization, and teamwork were essential.

## **EDUCATION**

**Bootcamp Certificate:** University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL 2020 **Bachelor's Degree:** Towson University, Towson, MD 2011